ABIOYE OBALOLUWA PETER

Lagos, Nigeria

(+234) 817 588 5645 ♦ abioyeobaloluwapeter@gmail.com ♦ Personal website ♦ Github ♦ LinkedIn

PERSONAL PROFILE

Experienced quality assurance engineer with over 4 years track record in agile testing across FinTech, GovTech, Ecommerce, and CRM software, adept at defect identification, analysis, and documentation, possessing strong analytical, manual and automation testing skills, effective communication, keen attention to detail, and collaborative teamwork abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web Automation testing: Cypress, Selenium WebDriver, Katalon
- Mobile Automation testing: Appium, UIAutomator2, XCUITest
- · Language: Javascript, C#, Java, Python
- · Load testing: JMeter, LoadView
- · Defect tracking and reporting: Jira, Click up, Jam
- Documentation: Confluence, MS Office
 API testing: Postman API, Rest Assured
- · CI/CD: Team City, Jenkins, Azure Devops
- · Database Testing: SQL
- · Test Framework: TestNG, NUnit, JUnit, Mocha, Cucumber

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University (OAU) - Ile-Ife, Osun State, Nigeria Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering CGPA - 4.36/5.0 (Top 5%)

Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2020

- · Dissertation: Design specification for an M-Health Solution to Improve Antenatal Care.
- Relevant Courses: Digital computer systems, Signal and Systems, Microprocessor technology, Data Structures and Algorithms, Applied Electricity, Computer Networks, Microelectronics Devices and Circuits, Natural Language Processing and its application, Artificial Intelligence, Engineering Analysis, Operating system principles.
- · Academic Leadership: Served as the Class Representative from 2015 to 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rayda – County of Sussex, Delaware, United States

Aug. 2023 - Present

Quality Assurance Engineer

- Analyzed project requirements and user stories to understand the scope of testing and identify potential areas of focus within our asset purchasing, asset management and asset disposal app.
- Developed test plans and strategies tailored to the eCommerce app, outlining testing objectives, timelines, and resources required.
- Created detailed and comprehensive test cases covering various aspects of the asset purchasing app, including user interface, functionality, and integration with third party systems.
- Conducted comprehensive manual e2e testing of our asset purchasing app within a Direct-to-Consumer (DTC)
 environment, focusing on product catalog management, shopping cart and check out process, shipping, and delivery
 etc.
- Reported identified defects accurately using Clickup, providing clear and concise information for developers to replicate and resolve issues promptly by integrating Clickup with Jam bug reporting tool.
- Participated in regression testing cycles to validate bug fixes and ensured the stability of the app across multiple releases.
- Conducted an extensive load and stress test on the app to ensure the app could handle concurrent user traffic using imeter.
- Developed a comprehensive test automation framework with Cypress using page object model and Cucumber BDD.
- Conducted engaging and informative demo sessions with consumers to showcase the eCommerce platform features and functionalities.
- Demonstrated key product offerings to prospective clients, resulting in a 20% increase in product sales.
- Trained sales and customer support teams on product features and benefits, enhancing their ability to effectively communicate with clients.
- Gathered feedback from consumers during demo sessions, facilitating the identification of pain points and areas for improvement.

Lead Quality Assurance Engineer

- Led a team of QA engineers and provided guidance, and technical expertise to ensure the successful delivery of high-quality applications under test.
- Collaborated with the development team and product owners to define test strategies, test plans, and test scenarios for an investment mobile app.
- Conducted code reviews and provided feedback to team members on test automation scripts and frameworks developed using Appium, TestNG, UIAutomator2 driver and XCUITest.
- Managed the staging environment, including mobile devices, emulators, and test data, to support comprehensive mobile app testing.
- · Integrated and implemented test reporting using Extent Reports library.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including development, product management, and UX/UI design, to ensure alignment on quality goals and requirements.
- Implemented continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines using Azure DevOps to automate the build, test, and deployment processes.
- Utilized github as the source code repository, managing version control, branching, and merging for the test automation codebase.
- · Conducted performance testing and load testing to ensure the app's stability and responsiveness under different usage scenarios using jmeter.

Qore - Lekki, Lagos, Nigeria

May 2020 - Feb. 2022

Quality Assurance Engineer

- · Responsible for a group of 3 testers; assign tasks to the team, review test cases, and optimize if necessary
- · Manual execution of test cases based on the software requirement document.
- · Extensively performed Regression, Exploratory, Load, Performance, API, and Smoke testing
- · Development of a traceability matrix to ensure all requirements are fulfilled.
- · Defect tracking using Jira; Creating, prioritizing, and assigning bugs.
- · Responsible for E2E test automation framework with 100+ Test cases for over 10 financial institutions.
- · 50+ Test Cases running daily in CI/CD (Katalon, Cucumber, Team city, and Git)
- Implemented various frameworks such as Data driven, Keyword Driven, and Behavioral Driven Development with Katalon
- Developed reusable and generic methods that can be used across the automation framework which increased automation test script development by 70% and reduced automation cost and maintenance by 30%
- · Trained and mentored new employees on the company's testing strategies
- Created test automation framework that handles card production, issuance, and personalization processes for over 10 financial institutions and increased regression test time by 50%
- · Reduced app server consumption by 50% and cut necessary costs by 20% within a year.

Sprinble – Lagos, Nigeria

April 2019 – December 2019

Software Engineer

- Built a teacher management web app using ASP.Net Core for the backend, AWS Services for media management, and React for the front end.
- Designed a simple domain-specific language to manage lesson contents for teachers.
- · Design and implementation of UI test automation framework using Cypress and Jenkins.
- · Regular interaction with the client to discuss functionality improvement.

RFM Network - Lagos, Nigeria

October 2018 - April 2019

Junior Network Engineer

- · Installed Point to Point Microwave radios for Diamond Bank, First Bank and Forte Oil.
- · Installed Point to Multipoint Ethernet microwave radio links.
- Developed an app that automated the process of extracting data from company mails and conversion to pdf files for record purpose and keeping up with company's SLA.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Audio compression using discrete cosine transform with temporal auditory masking

- Development of a system that compresses an audio signal using an algorithm that manipulates compression ratio, peak signal-to-noise ratio, and transmission delay.
- Built a UHF transmitter that sends the audio signal to a remote receiver, ensuring the compressed signal is lossless.

Dark Iris Recognition

- Developed an algorithm for iris segmentation using the integro-differential equations and circular hough transform
- Iris feature was extracted using principal component analysis and self-organizing map was used for iris template matching.

Car Accident Prevention Device

- Developed an android app that sends emergency notifications to registered mobile numbers in the occurrence of an accident.
- INodeMCU and Sim808 GPS/GSM module were used to detect the exact location of the accident in real time.
- · MPU-6050 gyro, Flame sensor, and MQ2 gas sensor were used for the detection and prediction of the accident.
- Firebase was used as the database to store sensor values.

Automated Water Level Monitoring device

- · Arduino was used in analyzing water level sensor values based on the configured thresholds.
- · Sim800l GSM module was used to send sms and voice notifications when water gets to a particular level.

Voice-controlled Home Automation

- Developed an android app to control and monitor the status of home appliances and devices connected to an arduino board.
- ESP8266 Wi-Fi module was used as the medium of communication.

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

Ishaya Gambo, Ekundayo Oluwole Ayegbusi, **Obaloluwa Abioye**, Theresa Omodunbi, Rhoda Ikono, Karen Olu-fokunbi (2022). Design Specification for an M-Health Solution to Improve Antenatal Care: Analytical and Technical Perspective. *Advancing Health Education With Telemedicine* - DOI: 10.4018/978-1-7998-8783-6.ch003;

EXTRACURRICULAR COURSES TAKEN

Intro to Selenium WebDriver with .NET Core	February, 2022
Introduction to Cypress	July, 2022
Advanced Cypress	July, 2022
Introduction to Blockchain Testing	July, 2022
Test Automation in DevOps	July, 2022
Selenium WebDriver with Java	October, 2022
Web Element Locator Strategies	October, 2022
Neural Networks and Deep Learning	October, 2022

AWARDS AND HONORS

2nd Runner up at AppZone About us challenge	2021
MTN Foundation Science and Technology Scholarship	2017-2020
Winner at the Bridge57 Young Engineers Session, Tech Conference OAU	2019
1st runner-up at Nigerian Fintech Competition	2019

LANGUAGES

English Language Advanced levels in Listening, Speaking, Reading, and Writing

REFERENCES